San Diego, CA

410.980.9672 (cell) bheussler@gmail.com

Summary

I am a software engineer that has been building Java applications professionally for seven years. Currently, I work for Swing AI. My most recent project is Swing Index, an on-demand mobile golf app. I also support Life Journey, building web applications used by hundreds of students on a daily basis. Java is my most proficient language, though I'm also comfortable on the front end. I'm actively working on a side project using Spring Boot and Vue.js, and writing about my experience on my personal website.

Relevant Experience

Swing Index Software Engineer LifeJourney / Swing AI

2018 - Present

- Designed, developed, and deployed a mobile app from the ground up, which now has 20,000 users and a 4.8 Rating on the Apple App Store and Google Play Store
- Built and maintained RESTful web services that the mobile apps use to process and persist user data
- Lead the design and development of the web application using Angular JS, which instructors use to score golf swings submitted by the users
- Implemented an asynchronous messaging system using Apache Kafka, which was used to process user videos and other backend services, and still provide a non-blocking experience to the user
- Integrated with the Google Play Developer API to provide verification of active user subscriptions
- Developed and modernized dozens of marketing websites, improving performance and maintainability

LifeJourney.us

LifeJourney / Swing AI

Software Engineer

2014 - Present

- Built and maintained web application in Java using Spring and Hibernate, capable of handling thousands of concurrent users by means of NGINX load balancing and multiple Tomcat servers
- Developed and maintained frontend in AngularJS
- Maintained 80% unit test coverage using JUnit and Jasmine on the back and front ends respectively, as well built integration tests using Geb and REST Assured
- Wrote migration scripts in Groovy that managed the migration of multiple versions of the application to satisfy multiple clients concurrently
- Built deployment scripts in Ruby using Capistrano to deploy the application to multiple environments

MatOnto Materials Science Framework

iNovex Information Systems 2012-2014

Software Developer

- Developed RESTful web services using Groovy on Grails that orchestrated CKAN data publishing
- Built ontologies serialized in RDF to enable federated SPARQL queries across multiple data sources
- Designed Accumulo powered Graph Data store to handle high volume integrated data

Skills

Languages: Java (Proficient), Javascript (Proficient), Groovy (Proficient), Kotlin (Familiar), Node.js (Competent), Ruby (Competent), HTML/CSS (Proficient), Sass (Proficient), SQL (Competent)

Frameworks & Libraries: Spring (Proficient), Hibernate (Proficient), AngularJS (Proficient), React (Familiar), Vue. is (Familiar), Bootstrap (Proficient), Gulp (Proficient), Webpack (Proficient)

Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Volunteer: Open Source Contributor for Twitter Bootstrap, Designer and Developer of https://usa505.org

Education

Connecticut College

New London, CT

B.A. Major Computer Science, Minor Economics (GPA 3.28)

2008 - 2012

- Relevant Courses: Computational Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence, Networks, Algorithms, Data Structures, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Software Engineering Methodologies